Shem Ogweno

FRONT END DEVELOPER

PROFILE

I am a Junior Fullstack Software Engineer with 4 years of experience.

I believe success is built through teamwork, collaboration and hard work, and I am always looking for opportunities to advance and grow my skills. I have strong communication skills and enjoy solving problems!

CONTACT

ogwenoshem@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/shemogweno https://github.com/ogwenos

EDUCATION

Sept 2019 - Sept 2021 Bachelors in Computer Science and Information Security

City University of New York, John Jay College

Jan 2017 - May 2019

Associates Degree in Computer Science

Borough of Manhattan Community
College

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Proficient in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Python, MySQL, HTML, Swift, JavaScript, CSS
- Proficient in frameworks & libraries: React, jQuery, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Bootstrap, Sass
- Comfortable using: Linux, Windows, Mac OS
- Experience in Google Analytics and web design
- Proficient in: Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator
- Fluent in Swahili, Luo and Kisii
- Completed Udemy Course: The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Junior Web Developer

CatPrint - Fairport, NY January 2022 - Present

- Involved in developing web application and software, utilizing Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, CSS3, and HTML5, React, Electron, MySQL, Jenkins, Git, and AWS
- Partnered with Marketing and Design and User Experience Design Teams to redesign and implement user interfaces
- Built RESTful APIs using Ruby on Rails for the front end to consume the JSON response
- Involved in bug research and fixing, in order to improve the user experience
- Involved in website optimization to improve the efficiency of operation and saving time
- Participated in code review sessions and improved the overall code reusability and maintainability
- Used CSS3 media queries and Flexbox API in order to maintain a responsive website in all screen sizes
- Involve in writing unit tests for Ruby on Rails code

Web Developement Menor

Volunteer - Remote December 2022 - Present

- Taught students remotely in web development using JavaScript, HTML & CSS
- Developed weekly lesson plans and projects to enhance the beginner learning experience, while creating single page applications

Camera Operator & Editor

BRIC TV - New York, NY May 2015 - March 2020

- Story boarded and worked alongside the director to assist in directing and filming 'Chef Roulet' cooking show
- Filmed short documentaries and live TV productions; trained and instructed assistant cameraman

Editor & Translator

The Documentary Group - New York, NY September 2017 - August 2018

- Translated footage into Swahili for feature documentary: "When Lambs Become Lions"
- Worked with the editor to advise on conversation flow